CHAPTER 3 A caucus race and a Long tail They were indeed a queer looking party
that assembled on the bank— —the birds with draggled feathers, the animals with
their fur clinging close to them, and all dripping wet, cross, and uncomfortable.
The first question of course was, how to get dry again: they had a consultation about this, and
after a few minutes it seemed quite natural to Alice to find herself talking
familiarly with them, as if she had known them all her life.
Indeed, she had quite a long argument with the Lorry who at last turned
sulcally and would only say, “I am older than you, and must know better;” and this
Alice would not allow without knowing how old it was, and, as the Lorry
positively refused to tell its age, there was no more to be said.
At last the Mouse, who seemed to be a person of authority among them, called
out sit down Sit down, all of you, and listen to me! I’ll soon make you dry
enough!” They all sat down at once, in a large ring, with the Mouse in the middle. Alice
kept her eyes anxiously fixed on it, for she felt sure she would catch a bad cold
if she did not get dry very soon said the Mouse with an important heir
are you all ready? This is the driest thing I know Sirens all around if you please!
‘William the Conqueror, whose cause was favored by the pope, was soon submitted
Dubai the English, who wanted leaders, and had been of late much accustomed to
usurpation and conquest Edward and Mork are the earls of America and Northumbria
said the Lorry with a shiver. “I beg your pardon!” said the Mouse, frowning, but very politely:
“Did you speak?” “Not I!” said the Lorry hastily. “I thought you did,” said the Mouse.
“—I proceed. ‘Edwin and morikar the earls of America and Northumbria, declared for him:
and even Stigand, the patriotic archbishop of Canterbury, found it
advisable—’” “Found what said the Duck. “Found it the Mouse replied rather crossly: “of
course you know what ‘it’ means.” “I know what ‘it’ means well enough, when I
find a thing,” said the Duck: “it’s generally a frog or a worm. The question
is, what did the archbishop find?” The Mouse did not notice this question,
but hurriedly went on, “‘—found it advisable to go with Edgar
aetholing to meet William and offer him the crown Williams conduct at first was
moderate. But the insolence of his Normans—’ How are you getting on now, my
dear?” it continued, turning to Alice as it spoke. “As wet as ever,” said Alice in a
melancholy tone: “it doesn’t seem to dry me at all.” “In that case,” said the Dodo solemnly,
rising to its feet, “I move that the meeting adjourn, for the immediate
adoption of more energetic remedies—” “Speak English!”
said the Eaglet. “I don’t know the meaning of half those long words, and, what’s more,
I don’t believe you do either!” And the Eaglet bent down its head to hide a smile:
some of the other birds tittered audibly.
“What I was going to say,” said the Dodo in an offended tone, “was it the best thing
to get us dry would be a caucus race What is a caucus race said Alice; not
that she wanted much to know, but the Dodo had paused as if it thought that
somebody ought to speak, and no one else seemed inclined to say anything.
“Why,” said the Dodo, “the best way to explain it is to do it.” (And, as you might
like to try the thing yourself, some winter day, I will tell you how the Dodo
managed it.) First it marked out a race course in a sort of circle, (“the exact
shape doesn’t matter,” it said,) and then all the party were placed along the
course, here and there. There was no “One, two, three in a way but they began
running when they liked, and left off when they liked However, when they had
been running half an hour or so, and were quite dry again, the Dodo suddenly called
out “The race is over!” and they all crowded round it, panting, and asking, “But who has won?”
This question the Dodo could not answer without a great deal of thought, and it
sat for a long time with one finger pressed upon its forehead (the position
in which you usually see Shakespeare, in the picture of him), while the rest waited in silence.
At last the Dodo said, Everybody has won, and all must have prizes.”
“But who is to give the prizes?” quite a chorus of voices asked. “Why, she of course,”
said the Dodo, pointing to Alice with one finger; and the whole party at once
crowded around her, calling out in a confused way, “Prizes! Prizes!”
Alice have no idea what to do, and in despair she put her hand in her pocket,
and pulled out a box of comfits, (luckily the saltwater had not got into it), and
handed them round as prizes. There was exactly one piece all round.
“But she must have a prize herself, you know,” said the Mouse. “Of course,” the Dodo
replied very gravely. “What else have you got in your pocket?” he went on, turning to
Alice. “Only a thimble,” said Alice sadly handed over here,” said the Dodo. Then they
all crowded round her once more, while the Dodo solemnly presented the thimble,
saying “We beg your acceptance of this elegant thimble;” and, when it had finished
this short speech, they all cheered.
Alice thought the whole thing very absurd, but they all looked so grave that
she did not dare to laugh; and, as she could not think of anything to say, she
simply bowed, and took the thimble, looking as solemn as she could.
The next thing was to eat the Comforts this caused some noise and confusion, as
the large birds complained that they could not taste theirs, and the small
ones choked and had to be padded on the back.
However, it was over at last, and they sat down again in a ring, and begged the
Mouse to tell them something more. “You promised to tell me your history, you
know,” said Alice, “and why is it you hate— —C
and D,” she added in a whisper, half afraid that it would be offended again.
“Mine is a long and sad tale!” said the Mouse, turning to Alice, and zying It is a
long tail, certainly,” said Alice, looking down with wonder at the Mouse’s tail; “but
why do you call it sad?” And she kept on puzzling about it while
the Mouse was speaking, so that her idea of the tale was something like this:—
“Fury said to a mouse, That he met in the
house, ‘Let us both go to law: I will prosecute you .—Come, I’ll take no denial;
We must have a trial: For really this morning I have nothing to do.’ Said the
mouth to the cur, ‘Such a trial, dear sir, With no jury or judge, would be wasting
our breath.’ ‘I’ll be judge, I’ll be jury,’
Said cunning old Fury: ‘I’ll try the whole cause, and condemn you to death.’”
“You are not attending!” said the Mouse to Alice severely. “What are you thinking of?”
“I beg your pardon,” said Alice very humbly: “you had got to the fifth bend, I think?” “I
had not! cried the mouth sharply and very angrily anat said Alice, always ready to make
herself useful, and looking anxiously about her. “Oh, do let me help to undo it!” “I
shall do nothing of the sort,” said the Mouse, getting up and walking away. “You
insult me by talking such nonsense!” “I didn’t mean it!” pleaded poor Alice. “But
you’re so easily offended, you know!” The Mouse only growled in reply. “Please
come back and finish your story!” Alice called after it; and the others all
joined in chorus oh Yes, please do!” but the Mouse only shook its head
impatiently, and walked a little quicker.
“What a pity it wouldn’t stay inside the Lorry as soon as it was quite out of
sight; and an old Crab took the opportunity of saying to her daughter “Ah,
my dear! Let this be a lesson to you never to lose your temper!” “Hold your
tongue, Ma!” said the young Crab, a little snappishly. “You’re enough to try the
patience of an oyster!” “I wish I had our diner here, I know I do!” said Alice aloud,
addressing nobody in particular sheets soon fetch it back!”
“And who is Dinah, if I might venture to ask the question?” said the Lorry Alice
replied eagerly, for she was always ready to talk about her pet: “Dinah’s our cat.
And she’s such a capital one for catching mice you can’t think! And I wish
you could see her after the birds! Why, she’ll eat a little bird as soon as look
at it!” This speech caused a remarkable sensation among the party. Some of the
birds hurried off at once: one old Magpie began wrapping itself up very carefully, remarking,
“I really must be getting home; the night air doesn’t suit my throat!” and a Canary
called out in a trembling voice to its children, “Come away call away, my dears!
It’s high time you were all in bed!” On various pretexts they all moved off,
and Alice was soon left alone.
“I wish I hadn’t mentioned Dinah!” she said to herself in a melancholy tone. “Nobody
seems to like her, down here, and I’m sure she’s the best cat in the world!
Oh, my dear Dinah! I wonder if I shall ever see you anymore
And here poor Alice began to cry again, for she felt very lonely and low-spirited.
In a little while, however, she again heard a little pattering of footsteps in
the distance, and she looked up eagerly, half hoping that the Mouse had changed
his mind, and was coming back to finish his story